<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apoorva Srinivasan</title>
    <atom:link href="http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://apoorvasrinivasan.com</link>
    <description>abstruse</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Why aren't you on whatsapp ?</title>
      <link>http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/telegram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/telegram/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time I tell anyone I have uninstalled WhatsApp, people wonder why. I type out a long list of features in reply. I am hence writing this to explain why i moved to Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who dont know, Telegram is an instant messaging​ service. It allows two or more people to chat. WhatsApp undoubtedly was the first internet based chat service that added contacts from the user’s phone book. Prior to WhatsApp there were other instant messaging services like MSN, gTalk, yahoo chat, etc. but these all required additional users to be created and invited. WhatsApp was well received and became really popular. But, here is the reason why I left it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;number sharing&lt;/strong&gt; : WhatsApp does not work without having to exchange your phone number with anyone you have to interact with. If you are a part of a large group for a trip or a project, then your number is visible to everyone part of that group.Gallery : WhatsApp creates a folder called WhatsApp images and videos and is part of the gallery. Any downloaded media is then gets amongst rest of your personal photos. It gets difficult to not only clean them later, your gallery also seems crowded. Anyone going through some album gets access to the junk downloaded by WhatsApp media . Of Course there is an option to not let media get downloaded but the thumbnail is quite blurred and you do end up clicking on it. Once the image is downloaded, you can delete it, but then it there is no option of re-downloading it EVER.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;multiple devices&lt;/strong&gt; : WhatsApp doesn’t work on multiple devices. One phone number is allowed exactly one WhatsApp account and one phone device. If you change your phone, and install WhatsApp on some other device, the previous app throws error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;web.whatsapp&lt;/strong&gt; : Webwhatsapp is a feature to allow you to access their WhatsApp messenger from web browser. THEIR MESSENGER. Which means, the device should be up and running with active internet connection for the web to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook Integration&lt;/strong&gt; : Since Facebook purchased WhatsApp, there were rumours user data being compromised and facebook using personal phone and contacts data to recommend friends on facebook. Although I don’t even have an FB account, this still seemed a little breach of privacy. This is also an problem since many of us maintaing two different set of friends and image over facebook and WhatsApp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-love-telegram&quot;&gt;Why i love Telegram&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets start with how telegram covers up for these drawbacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;number-sharing&quot;&gt;Number sharing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telegram works on an username basis. You can set your username. Anyone can chat with you by searching for you by your username. yes, this does allow random unknown people to chat, but responding to them is up to you, and you can always block the annoying ones.You can be a part of as many groups , only people in your contacts will be able to see your phone number. People do not need your number to add you to groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;Gallery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telegram does not download media in the gallery. You can select the photos and click on &lt;code&gt;save to device&lt;/code&gt; and only those would appear in the gallery. Rest of the media is saved in &lt;code&gt;/storage/telegram&lt;/code&gt; and can be cleaned whenever phone memory gets full.media never gets deleted : If you click on a media and delete it , you can click on it again and it will get downloaded again. The shared media tab stores the history of shared media amongst the people or the group. Deleted media would have a blurred thumbnail and would get downloaded again from the source on clicking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;devices&quot;&gt;Devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telegram app can be installed in as many devices as you like. The details of active sessions can be viewed from the settings menu.Telegram also offers desktop apps and web telegram. Every session runs independent of each other and does not require the phone device to be even switched on. It is very convenient to access and chat while doing other work.It will send a pass code for the initial set up which can be received over SMS or any other telegram instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-exciting-features&quot;&gt;Other exciting features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the above, telegram has really exciting features that glues people to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;stickers&quot;&gt;Stickers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chatting is all about conveying emotions and one emoji can have multiple interpretations. Telegram allows stickers and sticker packs to display exactly the feeling you wish to convey. Any one can create their own sticker packs with their custom images or choose from a variety of packs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;chatting&quot;&gt;Chatting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deleting chats&lt;/strong&gt; This is my personal favourite feature of telegram . It allows the sent and delivered messages to be deleted. Even in case of groups, the sent message can be deleted for all the members of the group without a trace. Read messages would also get deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;editing&lt;/strong&gt; Sent messages can be edited. any spelling mistake can be corrected easily without having to send another message with the corrected text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;code highlight&lt;/strong&gt; just like markdown, bold ( ** ) , italics (__) and code (“) works on telegram chats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draft&lt;/strong&gt; Telegram saves unsent messages as drafts. This draft is synced with all active telegram sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;auto preview&lt;/strong&gt; It previews any link sent. These links can be later accessed under the shared links tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dp-editing&quot;&gt;DP Editing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telegram allows you to completely edit your profile picture before posting. This includes cropping, brightness, contrast etc. It also saves the history of all the profile pictures that you have posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;secret-chats&quot;&gt;Secret Chats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it is for app only timer can be set and messages in a secret chat will get destructed from both ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;app-lock&quot;&gt;app lock&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telegram apps can have an extra layer of security pass code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;bots&quot;&gt;BOTS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gifs bot&lt;/strong&gt; 
like stickers , telegram also has gif bot . Just type &lt;code&gt;@gif &amp;lt;query&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and you will get a list of amazing funny gifs to share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inline Games&lt;/strong&gt; 
Allows you to play games like tic tac toe and rock paper scissors with your friends. Just type &lt;code&gt;@inlinegamesbot&lt;/code&gt; and choose a game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open source&lt;/strong&gt;
Telegram has bot APIs which allows users to code and share their own bots like github bot, game bot, gif bot etc. You can add any game bot as a member of any group and start playing with your friends!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-no-one-is-here&quot;&gt;but no one is here&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one response I get when I say all these to people, it that “not all people are there”. I hope this helps your friends to migrate as well :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object oriented analysis and design ......</title>
      <link>http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/uml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/uml/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its been a month&lt;br&gt;n it seems like a year&lt;br&gt;there is a limit to what&lt;br&gt;the students can bear :@  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;m getting bored&lt;br&gt;n in no mood to study :&lt;br&gt;n my head is spinning&lt;br&gt;away like an eddy:o  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the set of e-books,&lt;br&gt;together, they daun&lt;br&gt;the classes terrorize&lt;br&gt;and the obzects haunt x-(  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a word further can&lt;br&gt;now go into my head&lt;br&gt;this subject has successfully&lt;br&gt;turned my processors dead.. /)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this weird stuff&lt;br&gt;irritating to the core&lt;br&gt;n i say to myself,&lt;br&gt;“WHAT  MORE..!!!” B)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;booch n waghmare&lt;br&gt;have different views&lt;br&gt;the  use-cases diagrams&lt;br&gt;are actually of no use :(  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Question is :&lt;br&gt;what class avg would be??&lt;br&gt;just 2 more days and&lt;br&gt;we will be free..!!!!!  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running Away</title>
      <link>http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/running_away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 16:35:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/running_away/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running away from boredom… running away from monotony&lt;br&gt;Running away in search of an adventurous journey&lt;br&gt;Running away from alloo tikki, gol gappes n chat&lt;br&gt;to water the mouth with vada pao and lassan chutney…&lt;br&gt;Running away from glass and canvas&lt;br&gt;to the endeavor the art of warli……..&lt;br&gt;to undo the change this city has brought me to&lt;br&gt;Sometimes running away is all you can do……….:o :o  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running away from mark sheets, that gave no gain&lt;br&gt;Running away from the place whose memories remain&lt;br&gt;Running away from the bitch who ripped our soul apart&lt;br&gt;dilapidated our soul n made our life hap-hazard&lt;br&gt;i wish i could kill her without leaving a clue…&lt;br&gt;but running away is all i can do..:P:D;)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MY parents who have protected me for years&lt;br&gt;gave me all the happiness n wiped all my tears…&lt;br&gt;I’ll miss my bro… my..mom.. my..dad..&lt;br&gt;i know u’ll miss me too…, oh! am glad!&lt;br&gt;there’l be no1 to scold.. no one to argue..&lt;br&gt;but running away is all that i can do… :(:(  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;not to forget those who were by my side&lt;br&gt;the craazziest people who fight, help n guide&lt;br&gt;we “discuss” matters for hrs n yet can’t decide&lt;br&gt;life without them is a roller coaster ride…:D&lt;br&gt;m leaving open wounds that might not heal&lt;br&gt;Running away from u guys was never a fair deal.. :(  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the days… when i could c&lt;br&gt;the spark in your eyes while u look at me&lt;br&gt;your innocent smile in my presence&lt;br&gt;n your hair sticking out like medusa’s serpents&lt;br&gt;your unwanted high attitude n your low iq&lt;br&gt;getting away from u is most sensible thing to do.. :P :P  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M taking with me the memories. :)&lt;br&gt;m taking with me the experience.:)&lt;br&gt;what all this city has given me&lt;br&gt;Cannot be expressed in one sentence&lt;br&gt;m sure i’ll write a miss you poem soon&lt;br&gt;But for now running away is all i can do……  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'm Waiting</title>
      <link>http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 16:35:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/waiting/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m still waiting&lt;br&gt;For that call&lt;br&gt;One that’ll probably&lt;br&gt;Change it all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still waiting&lt;br&gt;For that rose&lt;br&gt;Filled with love&lt;br&gt;Or a little prose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still waiting&lt;br&gt;to hear that line&lt;br&gt;that will perhaps&lt;br&gt;make u mine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still waiting&lt;br&gt;For the invite&lt;br&gt;If I’m ready to walk&lt;br&gt;With you in the moon-light&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still waiting&lt;br&gt;to be missed&lt;br&gt;or to be noticed&lt;br&gt;that i exist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still waiting&lt;br&gt;for nothing more&lt;br&gt;but to make things&lt;br&gt;same as before&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been sitting here&lt;br&gt;Waiting quietly&lt;br&gt;Waiting for YOU&lt;br&gt;Waiting for you to notice me….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 idiots.. 1 class...and many more f*** ups</title>
      <link>http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/30-idiots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 16:35:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://apoorvasrinivasan.com/stuff/articles/30-idiots/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3 years ago I thought,&lt;br&gt;life was just a continuous function.&lt;br&gt;Until I found a goto statement&lt;br&gt;and landed at the Rajguru junction.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The call was perhaps required&lt;br&gt;to blendTrans many changes.&lt;br&gt;I was once a boolean variable,&lt;br&gt;now I am array of different ranges.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M not a poet and n I don’t claim to be.&lt;br&gt;Its just a 4KB tribute to u from me.&lt;br&gt;It has no rhyming scheme or poetic essence&lt;br&gt;and the Grammar used is purely Context Free  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I hope u’l still treasure it&lt;br&gt;somewhere in your vector subspace&lt;br&gt;n re-live the Moments Generated&lt;br&gt;in this blood sucking place.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonder what attributes our classes contain?!?!&lt;br&gt;confused students, teachers insane:&lt;br&gt;thinking throughout the semester,&lt;br&gt;“WILL I EVER USE THIS CRAP AGAIN????”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;photostats, assignments, songs and messages&lt;br&gt;were always in a deadlock&lt;br&gt;spent classes yawing, eating&lt;br&gt;and looking the Big O’ clock  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tolerating all our Gloria Mundi&lt;br&gt;just for an attendance score&lt;br&gt;Sorry ma’am, but STATS classes&lt;br&gt;were seriously a BORE  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During test, together we sat&lt;br&gt;without any shame…&lt;br&gt;coz conventionally, the ones&lt;br&gt;along the row… win the Game  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Lab Down is place where&lt;br&gt;smuggled in pd,food n belongings..&lt;br&gt;&amp;amp; we were religiously taught how to&lt;br&gt;correct the errors but ignore the warnings!!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normalizing our broken chairs.&lt;br&gt;Undue work piled up in cache.&lt;br&gt;Try to enter in the 11th hr&lt;br&gt;Ohh!!..u r turned out…. $$-bash  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We r simply overloaded and overridden&lt;br&gt;with tests n assignments but no hols are given&lt;br&gt;and still the teachers fail to understand&lt;br&gt;why our marks aren’t so grand  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These 6 sems, a lot they taught:-&lt;br&gt;Strengthen the friendship after huge fught fought&lt;br&gt;How to smile even if u flunk&lt;br&gt;N the pleasure of coming on a MASS BUNK  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did all our sharing n caring&lt;br&gt;with limited print out sheets&lt;br&gt;and tuned our TIME_WAIT states&lt;br&gt;with the amazing dhol beats  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our diverse talents has surely made our colg proud&lt;br&gt;be it studying hard or hardly or dancing along with the crowd&lt;br&gt;Every aspect of our talent has enthusiastically been presented&lt;br&gt;No matter how much, CS has been neglected…  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms Fresher, Ms Tapori n Spark of the Day..&lt;br&gt;certs too have a huge collection&lt;br&gt;and helping each other on exam eve&lt;br&gt;without any if-else condition  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together all of us have taken&lt;br&gt;computers to a new Branch.&lt;br&gt;This what exactly is called&lt;br&gt;a perfect Tech Mélange  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the clocks have ticked,&lt;br&gt;n its time for us to part&lt;br&gt;I bid u all farewell&lt;br&gt;with a heavy heart  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish u great, wherever u go.&lt;br&gt;Strengthen ur assets &amp;amp; set ur debentures low.&lt;br&gt;Differentiate the hurdles that come your way&lt;br&gt;&amp;amp; remember, client becomes a server someday  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon we’ll diverge, in the world, we’ll diffuse&lt;br&gt;so lets empty our stacks, n clear our queues&lt;br&gt;if at all we collide in future near or far&lt;br&gt;it’ll b purely coz of our implicit reference power…  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s share the last chilly aloo n andar wali chai
Sort the indifferences, smile and say good-bye&lt;br&gt;Not just a degree, but lot of memories I shall take&lt;br&gt;I’l now terminate bugging u guys.. Control + Pause Break  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>